# ADAM D'COSTA

# JUNIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

BRISTOL, UK

adamdcosta.github.io/adam-dcostaportfolio

# **TECH STACK**

HTML

CSS/SCSS

**JAVASCRIPT** 

**REACT** 

**JAVA** 

GIT/GITHUB FLOW

TDD

**JEST** 

**CYPRESS** 

**SKILLS** 

Buying

**Customer Service** 

Excel

Merchandising

Full clean UK driving license

### **INTERESTS**

Reading

Nature

Sports

Food

#### **PROFILE**

After 8 years of working in bookselling, a desire to build on new skills learnt during lockdown lead me to the decision to retrain and start a new career by enrolling on the twelve-week software development course with \_nology. The course gave me the confidence that I've made the right decision to change career; that I relish the prospect of building something that is used by other people and has an impact on their lives. I'm a quick learner with a customer-focused, flexible skillset developed in previous roles, as well as experience working in teams. I'm looking forward to starting my first role in tech.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# \_nology

JUNIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Aug 2021 - Nov 2021

An intensive 12-week software development course giving me a solid foundation in both front-end and back-end development. The course involved learning HTML, CSS/SCSS and Javascript before moving onto React and then Java, where we built our own API. We worked a on a live client project in which I was product owner for the final week and delivery of the project.

# Foyles Bookshop AREA COMMERCIAL SUPPORT

Sept 2019 - July 2021

Supporting shop teams through effective buying, ordering, communication, and training to ensure consistent commercial offers across all departments of the six-floored flagship store. I worked closely with the store management team on specific projects and to drive improvements – for example planning and implementing a new layout of the flagship store in order to drive sales of new and bestselling titles whilst also setting merchandising standards. I acted as a conduit for communication between head office and shop teams.

#### **HEAD OF PROMOTIONS**

Sept 2017 - Sept 2019

Responsible for planning, co-ordination and maintenance of the key Front of House and departmental display areas at the flagship store, as well as ordering and negotiating margin. Outlining a strong, title-driven promotional plan, that supports the store and company's overall strategy and works in line with key publishing dates and seasonal peaks. Working on projects with external and internal stakeholders to bring together cross-platform promotions.

#### **FOYLES BOOKSHOP**

May 2013 - Sept 2017

Enjoyed various customer-focused roles including Bookseller, Duty Manager and Supervisor.

### **EDUCATION**

**London Metropolitan University** 

September 2009 - June 2012

BA(Hons) Illustration – First Class Honours

**Stroud College** 

September 2008 - July 2009

Foundation Diploma in Art and Design – Distinction

KLB School – Wotton-under-Edge

September 2001 – July 2008

A Levels - Fine Art(A), Graphic Art (A), Maths(C), French-AS(B). GCSEs - 4 A\* grades, 8 A grades